clearias.com 2019-11-13

# Privacy Policy - ClearIAS.com

We at www.clearias.com are committed to protect the privacy of our visitors and handle all information with great responsibility. We believe it is important for you to understand what information we collect from you, how it is used and who will have access to that information.

Please note that this privacy policy applies to all products from Clear IAS, including our website www.clearias.com, www.cleariasexam.com and our mobile app ‘Clear IAS’, unless specified separately.

### Type of information we collect, if any

We do not collect or retain any personal information unless you choose to provide it to us.

**Non-personally identifiable information –** When you visit our website (www.clearias.com), it collects and stores non-personally identifiable information such as the name of the domain or IP address from which you access the Internet, the date and time you access our website, the browser version used, the device type (laptop or mobile) etc. We use this information to track the number of visitors to the different pages of our website. This helps us to make our website more convenient for users.

**Personally identifiable information –**  If you subscribe to this website (clearias.com) to get emails, buy ebooks from ClearIAS Online Store (instamojo.com/clearias) or register in our mock exam platform (cleariasexam.com), we collect the information that you provide – which may include name, username, email address, postal address, telephone number etc. The main purpose is to help the users themselves. If registered users forget their password, details like username or email are necessary to retrieve it.

### **Collection and Use of Personal Information**

By using the services of ClearIAS.com (and our partner websites like ClearIASexam.com, instamojo.com/clearias etc), you agree that any personal data collected will be used by us to contact you via phone, SMS or email for marketing and to deliver certain updates for services or information you have requested.

Your personal information is used to provide the services you request (Eg: to reset your password, to get ebooks delivered, to get mock exam results etc). This will also help us enhance this website. We also use your personal information to send updates like new posts, information about exams, promotional offers etc. By using our services, you agree to receive transactional as well as promotional SMS, Emails, Phone calls etc from us.

At times other companies may be hired to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings. We will only provide those companies with the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

We are committed to taking steps to protect the personal information we hold from misuse and loss and from unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.

### Third Party data collection

Third parties (For example, Amazon, or Flipkart) may be placing and reading cookies on our users’ browsers or using web beacons to collect information as a result of ad serving on this website.

As part of our own marketing efforts, we may share customer information with third parties to perform services on your behalf (Eg: Google, Facebook etc), but ensure that any personally identifiable information is not misused. Usually, our partner companies encrypt any personally identifiable information so that they are not misused.

### **To Further Protect Your Privacy**

While exploring this website, please be aware that third-party Internet sites and third-party services accessible through this website have separate privacy and data collection policies and practices. These policies and practices are independent of and may be different from the policies and practices for this website. We are not responsible or liable for these independent policies and practices and it is your responsibility to review them and decide whether or not they satisfactorily protect your rights.

### Changes to This Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time, and when such a change is made we will post a revised version on this website. Changes will be effective when they are posted. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy from time to time to be aware of any such changes. Your continued use of the website indicates your agreement to any such changes. If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us.
